# Bruno P. Kinoshita

(021) 104 2131 • ☑ kinow@apache.org • ☑ kinoshita.eti.br
in brunopkinoshita • ৺ kinow • ☑ kinow
Brazilian, married, 33 years old, non-smoker

I am an honest, and focused Software Engineer that is always trying to deliver solutions with quality. I am very calm and easy-going, and enjoy a challenging work environment, Open Source, and learning about different cultures.

I have worked in many different projects for the past ten years, in fields such as telecommunications, banking, credit, retail, insurance, and start-ups. Occupied different positions including programmer, quality engineer, devops, architect, full stack developer, and big data engineer.

I am fluent in English and Portuguese, with good understanding of Spanish, and basic of Japanese.

## **Skills**

Languages Java, Python, PHP, R, C/C++, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, Shell, Perl, SQL Frameworks Node.js, NumPy, Pandas, Spark, Spring, Struts, Hadoop, Tornado, Laravel PostGIS, WFS, WMS, SOS, and other OGC standards

Systems Linux, OSX, Windows

#### **Achievements**

o Invited to become an Apache OpenNLP PMC	July 2017
o Invited to become an Apache OpenNLP Committer	April 2017
o Invited to become an Apache Commons PMC	October 2016
o Invited to become an Apache Jena PMC	March 2015
o Invited to become an Apache Jena Committer	January 2015
o Invited to become an Apache Commons Committer	August 2012
o Organized two Jenkins meetups in Sao Paulo, Brazil	2012 and 2013

## **Awards**

o Spirit of GovHack for amazing team work. Auckland, New Zealand.	July 2016
o NIWA Proactive Communicator. Auckland, New Zealand.	February 2016

## **Education**

o Diploma in Business Administration, Mackenzie University	January 2008 – July 2009
o B.S. in Information Systems, Mackenzie University	August 2003 – July 2007
o Colegio Centenario (Sao Paulo, Sao Paulo, Brazil)	December 2002

## **Work Experience**

#### o Java Engineer, NIWA

Jun 2017 - Jun 2018

- Java development in the IT Systems Development team. Working on **EcoConnect**, NIWA's specialist environmental forecasting and information service.

## o Full Stack Software Developer, Spark Ventures

Oct 2016 – Jun 2017

- Java development in the Platform team, crafting solutions common to all other teams.
- Integration between AWS KMS and Spring Boot applications.
- **New Relic** configuration to set up alerts and monitoring for all internal applications, and also for external services such as **Zuora**, **Stormpath**, and **Prismic**.
- Bamboo restructuration, adding groups, cleaning up users, automating a few tasks, and generating user and operational documentation.
- Review security of build system, Spring boot applications, and AWS resources.

### o Software Developer / Operations, N/WA

Apr 2015 - Sep 2016

- Responsible for the Continuous Integration and development pipeline in Jenkins.
- Introduced **monitoring** of the development lifecycle activities with dashboards written in Node.js and using the **Dashing** framework.
- Responsible for maintaining the middleware stack, including **GeoServer**, **GeoNetworks**, **IPT**, **PostGIS**, **SOS** servers, vocabulary servers, and other internal systems.
- Worked closely with researchers writing Python tools and utilities for weather, remote-sensing, tracking, data processing, and general automation.
- Review internal infrastructure looking for security problems.
- Created company first public **git** repositories under a new organization in GitHub.
- o **Senior Big Data Engineer**, Boa Vista Servicos (Equifax)

Jun 2014 – Mar 2015

- Deployed a 8-node **Hadoop** cluster, with **Hive**, **Impala**, and **HDFS**.
- Created ontologies to match the data in the cluster with the data modeled by the data architecture department.
- Wrote web applications in Java with **Jersey** and **JOOQ**, and in PHP with **Laravel** to interface with the data generated after it was combined with the ontologies.
- Data ingestion automation with **crawlers** written in Python, parsing PDF files in Java with statistical tool.
- Meetings with internal departments to discuss project needs, and with external vendors to assess solutions, and RFP's and RFQ's
- Integrate Talend with Tableau, and IBM Nettezza
- Created monitoring dashboards for data arriving in the cluster
- Wrote initial jobs for parsing data collected by crawlers, combining with logs and other internal data dumps. Creating a benchmark, and comparison reports for the upper management.

#### o Senior Software Architect, Tokio Marine

Jan 2013 – May 2014

- Set up an **ActiveMQ** cluster with queues persisted in **Oracle**, and used by different internal departments.
- Participation in assessments for new solutions, and meetings with vendors.
- Organized internal workshops and trainings for the development teams.
- Created RESTful internal services for sending SMS, and signing PDF files.
- Set up the company SSO solution with **OpenAM**.
- Helped to set up authentication in **Liferay** with the new SSO solution.
- Created company-wide monitoring solution for both technical metrics and business KPI's.

#### o Senior Infrastructure Engineer, Tokio Marine

Oct 2012 - Dec 2013

- Automate infrastructure with **Shell**, **Jenkins**, and **Puppet**.
- Replace legacy OC4J servers by a new JBoss cluster.
- Update linux boxes to use services to start systems at startup, have a uniform logging settings, review log rotation settings, and integrated user authentication and sudoers.
- Automated parts of the software deployment that was a complete manual process before.

### o Senior Software Engineer, Tokio Marine

Oct 2011 - Sep 2012

- Helped to maintain legacy systems written for an internal portal solution.
- Mavenized systems written with Ant, Shell, and Ivy.
- Created **Subversion** hooks to trigger jobs in Jenkins.
- Created daily builds in Jenkins for the company portal.

## o Senior System Analyst, Lojas Riachuelo

Jul 2011 - Sep 2011

- Refactor old Java Swing application to improve threading and **OO design**.
- Suggest a different architecture for the company POS system written in Java.
- Split POS legacy system in Maven modules.
- Wrote first automated tests for the POS system.
- Create wrappers for the **Delphi** and **C/C++** devices used by the POS (e.g. printer, biometric devices).

## o Senior Software Quality Engineer, Vivo (Telefonica)

Jan 2010 - Jun 2011

- Gathering metrics from company CRM and modules, and analyse bugs and improvements
- Set up complete QA environment in **CentOS**, with tools such as **Hudson**, **Sonar**, **TestLink**, **FishEye**, and **JIRA**.
- Wrote an Open Source plugin for Jenkins to provide integration for TestLink
- Debug and profile the company CRM with YourKit, and Eclipse Memory Analyzer.
- Wrote performance tests with JMeter and SOAP-UI.
- Wrote company-wide tools to help different departments automating tasks.
- Participate in the company and partners RFP as technical person.

#### o Senior Software Engineer, Nossa Caixa Bank

Apr 2008 – Dec 2009

- Supported Java, C#, and Cobol developers in different departments.
- Wrote code standards for Java and **.NET** applications.
- Maintained integration code for Java and .NET with Mainframes using Cobol, **MQSeries**, **DirectConnect**, **Uniface**, and Java in Z/OS Linux.
- Developed Java training material, and provided training and interviews to other departments
- Assessment of new tools, providing detailed report to the bank decision makers.

#### o Junior System Analyst, Claro

Jun 2007 - Mar 2008

- Updated existing MMS adapter, to support new MMS/MM7 protocol in the VAS middleware system, using **Java**, **JEE**, memory buffers, and Java mail API.
- Added **JMS** configuration and code for the new MMS adapter.
- Helped mapping VAS to Billing process, looking for inconsistencies, and working with the revenue assurance team.
- Wrote a **Struts** application to manage broadcast SMS campaings, with scheduling **Quartz** and reporting **iReport**.
- Replaced company web site captcha and added a honeypot.
- Wrote Java code to ETL a complete corporation managed plans (Gestor Online) from Oracle.

#### o Junior System Technician, Claro

Jan 2006 - May 2007

- Wrote Java code for the JEE middleware platform Swing desktop application
- Troubleshoot **threading** issues in the desktop client.
- Wrote sockets, LDAP clients, and log parsers for the middleware server.
- Maintain the KPI's monitoring panel using applets, and accessed by upper management.

#### o Value Added Services intern, Claro

Jul 2004 - Dec 2005

- Internship in VAS, with a three month period working with on-going systems, learning how ticket systems work.
- Point of contact for local partners to set up their delivery channels in the VAS middleware system.
- Monitoring the VAS platform logs in HP-UX, Solaris, Linux, and Windows servers.
- Monthly and weekly reports for the VAS, on-going, Web, and upper management.

## **Technical Training**

o OWASP NZ Day Advanced Web Hacking and Secure Coding. University of Auckland. Au	ıckland,
New Zealand.	2017
o AWS Concepts. Linux Academy. Online.	2016
o Apache Spark Essentials. Linux Academy. Online.	2016
o CS107: C++ Programming. Saylor Academy. Online.	2016
o OWASP New Zealand day training. OWASP. Auckland, New Zealand.	2016
o Linux Foundation Certified Systems Engineer. Linux Academy. Online.	2015
o Infrastructure Management with Puppet. Instruct. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2012
o Basic concepts of change management. Nossa Caixa Bank. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2008
o CA Harvest Software Change Admin and Config. CA. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2008
o Hands-On Websphere Application Server. IBM. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2008
o Business Intelligence. Claro. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2008
o Information Security. Claro. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2007
o Biometry applied in computer networks security. Mackenzie University. Sao Paulo, Brazil. 2007	
o Web Development with Servlets and JSP. Sun Microsystems. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2007
o COBIT and Sarbanes-Oxley. Claro. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2006
o Genexus Programming. Procwork (Sonda). Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2004
o Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate career. Bras e Figueiredo. Sao Paulo, Brazil.	2003
Certifications	
o LFCE Linux Foundation Certified Engineer	2015
o Professional Scrum Master I (scrum.org)	2011
o ISTQB CTFL Certified Tester	2010
o SCWCD Sun Certified Web Component Developer	2009
o ITIL Foundation V2	2009
60 DIT 5 1 1 1 1/4 4	2006

## **Interests and Hobbies**

o COBIT Foundation V4.1

o Bioinformatics, semantic web, linked data, animation pipelines, NLP, fuzzy logic, and GIS.

2009

2008

2006

2003

o Sci-fi books, short stories, comics, movies.

o CA Software Change Manager Administration

o MCP Microsoft Certified Professional Windows 2000

o SCJP Sun Certified Java Programmer

- o Learning about new cultures, but in special Japanese, Brazilian, and Irish.
- o Slack line, swimming, judo, and soccer.

I wrote articles that have been published in different magazines, and also spoke in conferences in some countries. The complete list is available in my web site. For a list of Open Source projects that I contribute to, look at my GitHub profile. References available upon request.